Kenneth A. Schaefer II

Wichita Falls, TX, 76308 | kenneth.schaefer.ii@icloud.com | (317) 361-2543

PROFILE

A high performing manager and software engineer with a passion for all things IT and over 15 years of experience impacting positive outcomes through team building and attention to details. I am confident in the ability to collaborate with cross-functional teams in order to solve complex, high-stakes problems.

EXPERIENCE

Donald Jones Consulting

2021-PRESENT

General Manager / IT Consultant

- Enumerating and specifying procedures for the implementation, production and administration of written policies
- Properly controlling the release of proprietary information by organizing and developing information systems
- Providing meticulous reports and documentation for offsite owners of both the facility and the consultation company
- Analyzing and adjusting work procedures for maximum efficiency
- Effectively controlling costs through economical utilization of personnel, materials and equipment
- Planning, forecasting, setting objectives and determining best courses of action for the facility
- Developing enduring professional relationships with businesses and contractors

Trinity Executive Services

2020

Security Officer

- Coping effectively with pressure and tension between hospital staff and patients
- Firmly and fairly managing problems and disruptions while maintaining empathy towards the feelings of all parties
- Coordinating security protocols to comply with both HIPAA and Joint Commission standards
- Regularly assessing the development and effectiveness of subordinates while cultivating the strengths of individuals within the team

G3 Construction, inc.

2018-2020

Lead Commercial Foreman

- Planning, scheduling and assigning work for optimal distribution, staffing and efficiencies; consistently achieved deadlines, quality control goals, and produced quality inter-trade relations
- Holding meetings with clients to discuss/negotiate general contracts, purchase orders and subcontract agreements
- Closely monitoring budget variances and reports to maintain effective cost control
- Inspecting work in progress to ensure quality and conformity to contract and drawing specifications in accordance with federal guidelines
- Supervising crews of up to 10 carpenters, journeymen, drywall hangers, and general labor personnel

United States Marine Corps

2010-2018

Sergeant / Department Lead

- Creating and implementing IT programs to maintain OSHA compliance while accepting responsibility for compliance of regulations
- Creating an environment that encourages organizational readiness and individual mental health
- Maintaining morale and fostering relationships with both junior and senior Marines

- Closely monitoring and regulating federal operational and security guidelines within the restrictions of a Top Secret security clearance
- Assessing, organizing and arranging resources to effectively and efficiently maintain USMC and federal regulations
- Delegating responsibilities to junior Marines based upon their abilities and strengths to efficiently promote organizational needs
- Successfully handled demands from superiors and subordinates

EDUCATION

Amazon Web Services

2022

AWS Cloud Practitioner

Fullstack Academy

2022

Full Stack Software Engineer

Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University

2023

A. S. Engineering

SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Leadership
- Analytical Thinking
- Time Management
- Quality Assurance
- Attention to Detail